## **Triston Wasik**

## Full-Stack Software Engineer

## **Summary**

Experienced Software Developer/Analyst with a demonstrated history of working in the government administration industry. Skilled in Customer Service, Communication, Training, Management, and Software Development. Strong engineering professional with an Associates focused in Business Administration with a focus in Programming and Development from Eastern Gateway Community College.

## **Experience**

### **Software Engineer (contractual, non-permanent)**

**OK Candles** 

Mar 2022 - Present (4 months +)

Created the OKCandles official ecommerce website with Next.js. The website uses a Square to handle all web payments and orders, as well as managing products and stock values. The website information and content itself is managed through a Strapi.js headless CMS.

#### Software Engineer (contractual)

Freelance

Jan 2021 - Present (1 year 6 months +)

Worked for various clients such as RenegadeHosting and Epricot to create diverse software solutions and professional consulting to fulfill their business needs.

### Junior System Administrator (contractual, non-permanent)

Renegade Hosting

Nov 2012 - Present (9 years 8 months +)

Worked with users to set up Linux based virtual private servers (VPS), including answering technical queries and offering hands-on support. Completed tickets and interacted with end users in a professional manner including providing technical communications to non technical users.

## **Analyst/Programmer Flex I-IV (permanent)**

State of Alaska

Oct 2018 - Dec 2021 (3 years 3 months)

- Built the search functionality for the statewide internal Business Licensing system using .NET framework, Microsoft SQL Server, and Entity Framework.
- Helped maintain and improve all aspects of the Corporations, Business and Professional Licensing internal and external systems to service hundreds of thousands of licensees throughout the state. Estimated annual income from licensing is more than 10 million.
- Updated internal legacy systems to utilize RESTful APIs rather than direct database access to facilitate a merge to the Azure cloud.
- Assisted users through internal TrackIT ticketing systems with problems regarding software bugs and general maintenance requests.

### **Skills** - [github.com/TristonWasik]

Entity Framework • jQuery • jQuery UI • MySQL • Prisma • MVC • GitHub • Next.js • React.js • Git • Docker • CI/CD

#### **Volunteer Work**



### **Eagle River United Methodist Camp**

10+ years experience volunteering at the nature camp in Juneau Alaska. Roles performed: Camp Dean, Camp Director, Chief of Staff, Counselor, Vice President of the Board of Directors, Secretary of the Board of Directors

#### **Software Developer Mentor**

1 Year of Weekly or biweekly mentoring and teaching of software development, project management, and business analysis to aspiring developers.

## **Education**



# Eastern Gateway Community College

Associates, Business Administration with a focus in Programming and Development